Guide to David Earl Whitford Diaries
Erie Canal Museum
David Earl Whitford Diaries
1852 - 1940
Diaries written by David Earl Whitford and his children, Lizzie Whitford, Marie Whitford, and Oscar Whitford. David Earl Whitford was a New York State Engineer.
3 boxes
Whitford, David Earl, 1829-1913
Erie Canal Museum 318 Erie Boulevard East Syracuse, NY 13202
The Collection is open for research use.
David Earl Whitford (1829-1913) worked for the State of New York for 57 years in the engineering department. At the time of his death, he was known for serving the State longer than any other engineer. He was the Resident Engineer for the Middle Division from 1889-1894, and worked as the assistant to the City Engineer in Syracuse from 1879-1880
Erie Canal (N.Y.); New York (State). Department of Public Works
Seventy diaries belonging to David Earl Whitford and his children, Lizzie Whitford, Marie Whitford, and Oscar Whitford, dating from 1852 to 1940.
- Diaries
  - Diaries 1852-1859, 1850 - 1859
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1852, Item PC 1985.18.01 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1853, Item PC 1985.18.02 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1857, Item PC 1985.18.03 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1858, Item PC 1985.18.04 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1859, Item PC 1985.18.05 (Box 1)
  - Diaries 1860-1869
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1860, Item PC 1985.18.06 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1861, Item PC 1985.18.07 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1862, Item PC 1985.18.08 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1863, Item PC 1985.18.09 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1864, Item PC 1985.18.10 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1865, Item PC 1985.18.11 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1866, Item PC 1985.18.12 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1868, Item PC 1985.18.13 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1869, Item PC 1985.18.14 (Box 1)
    - Lizzie Whitford Diary 1869, Item PC 1985.18.57 (Box 3)
    - Marie Whitford Diary 1869, Item PC 1985.18.58 (Box 3)
  - Diaries 1870-1879
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1870, Item PC 1985.18.15 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1871, Item PC 1985.18.16 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1872, Item PC 1985.18.17 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1873, Item PC 1985.18.18 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1874, Item PC 1985.18.19 (Box 1)
    - Diary-No Name 1874, Item PC 1985.18.59 (Box 3)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1875, Item PC 1985.18.20 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1876, Item PC 1985.18.21 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1877, Item PC 1985.18.22 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1878, Item PC 1985.18.23 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1879, Item PC 1985.18.24 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Shooting Record Book 1870-1872, Item PC 1985.18.56 (Box 3)
  - Diaries 1880-1889
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1880, Item PC 1985.18.25 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1881, Item PC 1985.18.26 (Box 1)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1882, Item PC 1985.18.27 (Box 2)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1883, Item PC 1985.18.28 (Box 2)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1884, Item PC 1985.18.29 (Box 2)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1885, Item PC 1985.18.30 (Box 2)
    - Oscar Whitford Diary 1885, Item PC 1985.18.60 (Box 3)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1886, Item PC 1985.18.31 (Box 2)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1887, Item PC 1985.18.32 (Box 2)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1889, Item PC 1985.18.33 (Box 2)
  - Diaries 1890-1899
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1891, Item PC 1985.18.34 (Box 2)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1892, Item PC 1985.18.35 (Box 2)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1893, Item PC 1985.18.36 (Box 2)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1894, Item PC 1985.18.37 (Box 2)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1895, Item PC 1985.18.38 (Box 2)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1896, Item PC 1985.18.39 (Box 2)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1897, Item PC 1985.18.40 (Box 2)
    - Diary-No Name 1897, Item PC 1985.18.61 (Box 3)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1898, Item PC 1985.18.41 (Box 2)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1899, Item PC 1985.18.42 (Box 2)
    - Diary-No Name 1899, Item PC 1985.18.62 (Box 3)
  - Diaries 1900-1909
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1900, Item PC 1985.18.43 (Box 2)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1901, Item PC 1985.18.44 (Box 2)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1902, Item PC 1985.18.45 (Box 2)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1903, Item PC 1985.18.46 (Box 2)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1904, Item PC 1985.18.47 (Box 2)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1905, Item PC 1985.18.48 (Box 3)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1906, Item PC 1985.18.49 (Box 3)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1907, Item PC 1985.18.50 (Box 3)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1908, Item PC 1985.18.51 (Box 3)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1909, Item PC 1985.18.52 (Box 3)
    - Diary-No Name 1906, Item PC 1985.18.70 (Box 3)
  - Diaries 1910-1919
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1910, Item 1985.18.53 (Box 3)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1911, Item PC 1985.18.54 (Box 3)
    - David Earl Whitford Diary 1912, Item PC 1985.18.55 (Box 3)
    - Diary-No Name 1912, Item PC 1985.18.63 (Box 3)
  - Diaries 1930-1940
    - Diary-No Name 1930, Item PC 1985.18.64 (Box 3)
    - Diary-No Name 1931, Item PC 1985.18.65 (Box 3)
    - Diary-No Name 1932, Item PC 1985.18.66 (Box 3)
    - Diary-No Name 1934, Item PC 1985.18.67 (Box 3)
    - Diary-No Name 1935, Item PC 1985.18.68 (Box 3)
    - Diary-No Name 1940, Item PC 1985.18.69 (Box 3)